BEVAN JACINTO

+1(408) 387-3371 \diamond Santa Clara, CA

bevanjacinto98@gmail.com \left\right

OBJECTIVE

I am a software developer primarily focusing on building fullstack solutions using Angular and React along with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB. I also work on building cross-platform applications using Flutter, Dart and firebase for the backend. Over the course of my academic and professional career I have gained valuable expertise on these tools and with around 4 years of experience in building frontend and backend services I am eager to take on the next challenge that awaits me.

EDUCATION

Master of Science - Computer Science and Engineering, Santa Clara University Bachelor of Engineering - Information Technology, University of Mumbai

June 2023 October 2020

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, Typescript, Dart, C/C++, Windows, Linux

Database: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Angular, React, Bootstrap, Chakra UI, Material UI, NodeJS, Express, PHP, Ajax

Software and tools: AWS, Docker, Git/Github, Flutter, Figma, Vite, Redux, Arduino, XAMPP

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

SCU Frugal Innovation Hub

Jan 2022 - present Santa Clara, CA

- Developed dynamic and reusable buttons and forms using **React** and **Typescript** for an e-learning application to teach unprivileged children.
- Integrated Material-UI components to ensure a consistent and visually appealing design across the application.
- Created web interfaces using **HTML**, **CSS**, **Typescript** and **Bootstrap** to develop an internal UI for Frugal developers to update their weekly progress.
- Developing cross-platform full-stack applications using **Flutter** and **Dart**, with **Firebase** for backend support.
- Collaborated with non-profit organizations to create resource applications catering to people with disabilities.

Software Engineer

Rocket Central

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022 Detroit, MI

- Crafted validation scripts using **Joi** (data validator) for multiple forms in the mortgaging application flow using **Angular** and **Typescript** to ensure accurate prediction of mortgage rates.
- Used the **Rocket Mortgage API** to persist users mortgage application progress and data for smooth retrieval at a later point in the future.
- Leveraging Git and GitHub for code management, version control and continuous integration.
- Created different UI views using **HTML**, **CSS** and **Typescript** for different clients originating through one of the many Rocket Mortgage partners.

Software Engineer

Sep 2020 - Aug 2021

Reliance Jio

Mumbai, India

- Served as a software developer, responsible for implementing user interface (UI/UX) designs using **HTML**, **CSS**, **Bootstrap** and frontend technologies like **Angular**.
- Designed and developed Data Visualization Web Dashboards using Angular, TypeScript, and HighchartsJS.
- Created an API using **NodeJS** and **Express** to fetch application data from a **MongoDB** database to be integrated with the dashboards.
- These dashboards presented tabular and graphical representations of KPIs (Key Performance Indicators), such as User Retention and Churn Rate, for various Jio Media applications.
- Delivered an 80% reduction in manual queries and significantly improved the efficiency of report generation, enhancing the analysis of key performance metrics and aiding business decision-making for Jio products.

Jun 2019 - Feb 2020 *Mumbai*, *India*

Tata Consultancy Services

- Designed and developed **React** components using **HTML**, **CSS**, and **TypeScript** to enhance Tata Consultancy Services web pages, making it more user friendly.
- Created forms and dashboards using **React** and **Bootstrap**, facilitating seamless claim report filing for TCS's claims department, fostering improved communication between HR and 10,000 employees.
- Used **Git** for collaborative version control and code review, ensuring efficient code management.
- Utilized **NodeJS** and **Express** to develop **RESTful** services within **React**, enabling efficient retrieval of employee data across multiple pages, optimizing data management and accessibility of claim services.

PROJECTS

STOCK MARKET PREDICTION USING MACHINE LEARNING:

- Developed an LSTM model achieving an 85% prediction accuracy for stock prices using Python.
- Engineered a software application for deploying the machine learning model, leveraging Tkinter, Scikit-learn, Pandas, NumPy, and TensorFlow libraries.

MEDLABS:

- Created a dynamic website from the ground up, employing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for the front-end development.
- Engineered the back-end infrastructure of the website using PHP and MySQL, incorporating a robust shopping cart system.

GAME HUB:

- Developed a game listing website clone using React, Vite, and Typescript.
- Integrated frontend frameworks including Chakra UI and Bootstrap to enhance the user interface and experience.
- Implemented data fetching from the RAWG API to dynamically populate and display games in a grid format on the webpage.